Duc (David) Le

Full Stack Engineer

wa.me/+84973877428

✓ ducqhle@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/ducqhle

ducqhle.github.io

Summary

4 years of experience developing highly interactive applications using the latest web technologies. Contributed to more than 5 projects at world class had SEO optimized, high interactive UX/UI, great performance and full responsive. Not only by getting the task done but also constantly looking for ways to make it better. A long life leaner with the mindset that technology is to solving problems.

Work experience

Full Stack Engineer

2021-01 - present

Spiderbox Design

- Developed full responsive UI in various applications using different cutting edge technologies, included but not limited to ReactJS, TypeScript, NextJS, Formik, Yup, React Emotion, Material-UI, .NET Core.
- Added high quality code while continuously refactoring and adding unit tests.
- Actively reviewed code and supported across multiple teams.
- Quickly adapted with new technologies across repositories while performing various kind of requirements included React Native, D3JS, MJML, VueJS, PowerBI,...
- Investigated many complex front-end issues which required deep codebase knowledge and library API specifications (Ag-grid, MobX, Upgrade Material-UI version).
- Created the schedule and agenda for the ReactJS internship program.
- On-boarded new members with the front-end systems.

Software Engineer

2020-07 - 2021-01

Ubitec

- Participated in maintaining and developing the core features for the chatbot-platform with ReactJS, NodeJS, TypeScript, Microsoft Bot Framework, React Flow, Redux.
- Researched solutions in order to implement chatbot application requirements and systems required specifications.
- Added new code while keeping the code's coverage by include it along with the unit test which powered by Jest, React Testing Library and Fast Check.
- Configured CI/CD process using Jenkins, Docker, and integrate with Bitbucket, OpenShift.

Software Engineer

2018-09 - 2020-04

KMS Technology, Inc

- Developed end-to-end features, investigated issues full flow from back-end (.NET, NodeJS), database (MSQL) to front-end (ASP.NET).
- Migrated a .NET legacy system from monolith to cloud base service by using AWS Lambda, .NET core and NodelS.
- Built a AI chatbot assistant powered by Microsoft Cognitive Services and Microsoft Bot Framework to help administration team supporting employees with the knowledge base building around the FAQ documents.

Education

Bachelor's degree, Technology Information

2015-09 - 2018-06

University of Science

Certifications

- Udemy Certificate of Completion Learn and Understand NodeJS Udemy
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) Udemy
- The Complete Guide to Advanced React Component Patterns Udemy
- KMS Techcon Certificate of Appreciation

Volenteering

- Participated YouthSpeak Performance Charity Non-profit organization that provides performance opportunities for young people, focusing on issues such as social justice, mental health, and education
- Participated in Germer Non-profit organization with a mission to bring classical music closer to Vietnamese people.